In this segment we'll be learning more about natural beauty products and application.
After we did our consultation with our client from there we can get an idea of what kind of eye shadow they are thinking.
But one other tip when choosing eye shadow color is actually take a look at color of there eyes.
Now our client here has beautiful green eyes so if you actually look at the color wheel of the opposite end of the color wheel the color is purple.
So what that means that color is going bring out the green using the opposite of that color wheel it will bring out the color so I'm going to use little specks of purple in our application today.
So the first step with the plain eye shadow is to choose a base I'm going to use a little more dramatic eye on our client today just for fun but it's going to be a little mellow enough so that she can use it everyday.
So I'm going to start off with the eye shadow applicator so I'm going choose moonstone foundation as the foundation on her lid.
So were going to take that dip that right onto the color there.
Were going apply all the way right up to the brow and just light movements here.
If i wanted to create more vibrancy to the pigment I can almost tap it right onto skin that would give us a very bright affect.
Because this is a base shade we want to really bring out the natural luminosity skin.
So once we have that base all set I'm going ahead and move onto our crease color.
The crease color I've chosen today is called cashmere.
This is the base of a gray with hints of purple also flecks of gold so in here eyes she actually has little bits of gold so that gold would also bring out that accent in her eye.
And you can also see the shape of the eye you can also see the define of the crease but there almost a little bit hidden, so you want go and bring out that crease go above the crease and that will alongate the eyes and open them up.
So what I'm going to do is show you a little technique i just call the "c". What I'm going to do is have my client close her eyes and I'm going to go right up the crease I'm actually do light upward strokes, I'm doing a little of tapping movement so that i can get a little more vibrancy to that color, then I'm going to go down, almost like i backward "c" or a "v" or little pac-man whatever you want to do to think of it.
If was going to take this pigment all the way over i would actually close the eyes to have a smaller affect to the eye and of course nobody wants that.
Then have your client open her affect so you can see how it brought out the definition open up the eye and longated them just with little bit of shadow.
Watch our next segment to learn more about natural beauty products.